Omar Sheikh was born in Britain.
He studied at the London School of
Economics.
Then, in 1994, he was arrested in India
over the kidnapping of Western tourists.
The aim of that kidnapping was to force
the release of jailed militants.
Five years later, other men hijacked a
plane to force the release of him.
After Kandahar, he surfaced in Pakistan.
In January 2002,
Daniel Pearl,
a reporter for The Wall Street Journal,
was kidnapped in Karachi while
investigating militant networks.
Pearl was killed.
A Pakistani anti-terrorism court convicted
Sheikh that year and sentenced him to
death.
Then the case began to unravel.
In 2020, a high court overturned his
murder conviction.
In January 2021, Pakistan's Supreme Court
acquitted him.
According to the Committee to Protect
Journalists, he was moved to a government
"safe house" — under guard, but off death
row.